The next pose in our upper body strengthening and toning asana sequence is side plank.
Pretty self explanatory from the name.
If you know what plank pose is, it's your basic push up position.
You've got your wrist right under your shoulders and your body's in a straight line from your heels to the crown of your head.
So to come into side plank what you're going to do is say if I'm going to come into my...I'm going to bring my right side up and my left side down, right?
So I'm going to bring that left hand a little bit over to kind of the middle.
I'm going to start to shift my hips and let them open across the front.
I'm going to let this arm rise.
My feet are stacked.
I'm not like this, and I'm not like this, I'm still in that straight line -crown of my head all the way down through my heels.
Shifting to the other side, right hand down, left hand up.
See if you can come through each side a couple of times.
Remember when you're here to not let your hips break, stay solid through your core and let your breath flow.
Breath's key in this pose.
Inhaling and exhaling, keep those breaths long and strong, coming in and out through the nose, filling all the way down to the bottom of the belly, pushing all the air out on every exhale.
Breathe and flow.